[Music]
welcome to business one two once with OJ
Lopez and today we are very lucky to
have a very special guest and she has
been in the life insurance industry for
about 20 years previously she worked in
corporate sales and marketing uh she has
a seventeen year old girl and she likes
horror movie sci-fi and action movies
read self-help books and videos
I also likes traveling and shopping and
dining and ultimately she just wants to
make a difference in the lives of people
so without further ado I would like to
welcome mr. Stella C boa of FWD
insurance welcome to the show mom Stella
yes good morning Oh Jay and I'm very
happy to be in your show today thank you
so much for this very wonderful
opportunity given to me our pleasure our
pleasure so let's get on with it I mean
my first question to you is just to know
a little bit of history and we want to
know how did you get into life insurance
basically was a teacher about perfection
I graduated from Saint Teresa's College
BS e
educational and major in mathematics
they landed with the first job in
teaching for four years and after four
years I went to sales and marketing
that's where I got into sales and
marketing in somebody in
guided me at actually der there were
friends of mine before that actually
invited me to join the industry but of
course my perspective before was that
hey that's only good for people who
don't have a choice in life meaning
these are only for retirees that was my
perspective before but when I listened
to the presentation I just found out how
amazing the life insurance business is
okay so it was somebody that whom I
really didn't know that made me open my
eyes to see the value and the real
beauty of the business of life insurance
and there are very reason why I got into
this business because I was in corporate
sales for three years and the number one
reason was that I one time freedom okay
so because you are your own boss
and aside from that it is also the what
I call there's the unlimited income and
and most importantly the essence of
mission that you're going to give impact
to the people to the lives of the people
around you so basically these are the
three main reasons why I got into this
business Fred Wow Wow amazing amazing
background now what would you advise
people who are looking into having a
successful career in in life insurance I
mean I understand that you also have a
team right so for people out there or
looking into getting into the life
insurance business what a piece of
advice would you want to give them
well basically this is not for everyone
okay not everybody is cut out for this
kind of business because this is a
business that is actually very
challenging ybv challenging because you
are changing the perspective of people
all right so when you're going to change
your perspective the mindset of people
that is really that that makes it very
challenging now those people who would
like to enter in this business are those
people who really have this you know the
persistence meaning you have to process
in this business because a lot of
rejections are there so you'll be
flooded with a lot of rejections even
your own friends and relatives and even
families the worst are even I'm against
against into this kind of business
because they look at this business as
something that is not ideal no because
usually they always ask ok you have to
go to the corporate world and you have
to be an executive you have to be
manager in a corporate world so that's
the mindset of people because that's the
kind of programming we have because we
know everyone where before it was it has
been programmed that when you finish
your degree you should have you should
learn every good job right now at this
point in time it's not longer true you
know because a lot of people are
successful financially doing the
business and in fact in the insurance
industry there are a lot of millionaires
already an even businessman Chinese
businessman in fact professionalist
lawyers and doctors are actually
venturing into this kind of business but
of course first of all if you want to
join this business there must be the
change of mindset and perspectives about
life insurance you have to believe that
this is the best or in the best business
in the world you got to believe the the
sense of mission because
basically that what makes us sustain
when you're going to know your greatest
why why are you going to do this
business even amazed that this the
discouragements frustrations that you
encounter along the way you are grounded
strongly because of that belief because
of that greatest why's that it's not
just about simply making money but it is
basically making a difference in the
lives of people why because I would like
to tell you that in this business you
have the three eyes number one is that
impact you're making impact in the lives
of people and I would like to tell you
that along the way that how do you give
impact in the lives of people one is
that you are protecting the families
basically we're saving lives okay and
another thing also is the independence
meaning that you are your own boss
especially to those people who are tied
up to eight to five job this one in fact
like me for example I'm our mother I'm a
full-time mother and a full-time career
woman a businesswoman it has them
compromised my business I still do my
full-time mother who doing while doing
this business the third one is that the
income of course it offers you unlimited
income this is some business you may be
that if you put in hard work more time
and effort in this business it is
directly proportional to your income so
it's unlimited and aside from that for
example in my case I'm able to live the
life of a dreams because of doing this
business so I travel almost around the
world because of this business for free
and that makes us very you know and the
recognition that you can receive you
know that is something in your life that
money can't buy when people applaud you
for doing for being successful and
touching people's lives that is
something beyond compare
that's it so people who have this I just
like to summarize them meaning that
people who have the belief not do you
have to have the belief in the mission
of protecting lives or saving lives
second is that the courage to pursue
your dream because we need people who
are dreamers here and soft driven and
you need to be persistent and resilient
at the same time because there are a lot
of obstacles challenges you encounter in
this business
Wow yes it's very inspiring especially
for those who wants to betray a life
insurance as a career now let's go to
the other side of the coin talking about
your customers and the clients that you
serve so for for people out there what
is actually life insurance and why is it
important to have one Wow yes I do
believe that life insurance is always
part of the basic necessity it's just
like you know like you cannot live in
out water right you cannot leave it out
in fact now we cannot even live without
you no power so utilities are basic
necessities in fact insurance should be
part of the basic necessities and it's
really you know it's really paid it
really pains my heart that seeing people
making life insurance as the last
priority well in fact if you come to
think about the cash flow right they buy
your the cash in what is your cash in
during your salary or it could be the
income for your business right that's
your cash in and this cash will be used
for a cash outflow which is your basic
necessities like for example water food
utilities
like education come to think of it you
know that life is like ends right we are
all mortals so it's inevitable death is
inevitable when a breadwinner is taken
out of the picture oh look at so what
will happen to the income the income
goes with the breadwinner right agree
the sellers how what happens to the
necessities what what happens to the
needs of the family will it will this go
where the breadwinner or not they
continue right they continue now if
you're gonna put less insurance as part
of the cash out this is the only expense
that replaces the lost income that the
breadwinner is earning so it basically
life insurance as an income replacement
meaning that whenever the breadwinner is
gone there is the income that is going
to continue to be provided for the
family to go on with their lifestyle so
basically that's life insurance another
thing also is that life insurance is
basically securing the rest no like its
securing the risk of life what either is
number one the one that I mentioned is
death that is areas so and insurance is
the income replacement so that the
family can continue living on the same
lifestyle subcon another risk is getting
oh don't you know that getting old is
also a very big risk
why because based on statistics 90% it
totally broke when they reach the age of
75 60 and up so yes that's the
statistics now so what does life
insurance do life insurance is going to
secure your future by giving you by
providing you retirement fund so it's a
longer the same before that is only
talking about death people always say I
that life insurance is about is about
the people I live behind
but not really if you come to think of
it it's really about yourself
why because if you continue living if
you live long where will you get the
money to support your basic needs
okay so life insurance provides
retirement plan a retirement fund that
is going to give you the sense of
dignity that you can keep your dignity
as people as a person the third one is
that what is other the risk now is the
risk of getting critically ill meaning
if you get sick a lot of people have
liquidated their assets in order for
them to you know to finance the
medication I would say you have friends
and relatives out there that have
experienced that that they liquidated
their assets because you want to save
lives so life insurance is going to
protect you from you know like depleting
your assets but it's going to secure
your asses and making you afloat when
times in times when you're greatly
quickly ill okay another risk also that
you can appear tech of course this
another risk but it's also life ancients
can also help you secure the education
of your kids okay meaning that we can we
can help you dock because we're into
investment already life insurance must
investment this time it's so longer
before that is just protect just less
about death but now it's also talking
about living life to the fullest meaning
that whenever you want to grow your
money life insurance can help you with
that for the education of your kids last
but not the least of course this has
been overlooked you know people think
that if you are a big businessman and
you have so many assets you don't need
life insurance that has been the
perspective but nowadays come to think
of it a lot of rich people you know like
wealthy people really need life
insurance because why because when W
when the asset owner when the estate
owner dies their these assets that have
been accumulated for years when
go directly to the family these will go
to the government be I also have to pay
to pay the estate taxes so therefore in
order to for you to preserve the assets
of the assets for the family and making
them exclusive for them for your
beneficence for your heirs and heiresses
then you've got to secure a life
insurance that will take care of your
tax estate tax liabilities so it's
really for a state preservation life
insurance is for a state preservation
and conservation at the same time it's a
whole lot of things that the cover say
before you start that life insurance
will just give you benefits for your
beneficiaries when you know when you
leave this this world but from what you
have mentioned there's a lot of things
that that life insurance can cover and
later on let's talk about the company
FWB insurance and the products and
services it offers but before that I may
my question to you would be very
relevant in this day of age that's why
we are doing an online one to one
because of this are copied 19 pandemic
right and I know that that there's also
some FWD has taken the initiative also
to to customize a product amidst this
pandemic but again we'll talk about that
later let's let's talk about first how
is it affecting the insurance industry
maybe in your business or the the
industry as a fall and what what are you
guys doing to mitigate this situation
Wow that's really I think I've expecting
you to ask that question you know what
yes basically if you're looking at it
because we are into ezq enhanced
quarantine right community quarantine I
told that a lot of businesses have been
affected tremendously so we businesses
nowadays are compromised at first I was
personally I was apprehensive and was
quite anxious about it because you know
usually we have to meet our clients face
to face right and to get the signature
of our clients that we should be the
usual thing now along that way along
that way FWD is thinking of something
because you know FWD is a company that
is really ready for any situation given
know so with the covered 19 FWD was able
to method to keep the business even in
in this times you know why because I
asked WD was able to secure you know to
secure from issuance commission that we
are allowed to do remote selling meaning
that we are FWD is ready and to serve
you and protect all the clients or the
Filipinos by just having you know from
the comforts of their own homes meaning
that you don't need to see them
personally but it can set up a meeting
by just Val you're using like this like
the platform there this kind of platform
were in zoom video entry what I internet
you know so social media so we can do
that so we can continue so there is no
problem because our agents still
continue to earn and we still continue
to how to continue serving or advocacy
of helping Filipinos build a build a
financial future secure their lives and
their families we can continue that and
what's good thing you know what because
I'm so happy that seems FWD is
Digital was has been digital from the
very beginning we are more than ready to
do this kind of business because we are
fully digital and I would say this is
just nothing for FWD because we are
preparing for this kind of situation
that time will come that people will no
longer have face to face transaction but
you can just do it online so that's
where FWD is getting the competitive
advantage in the industry
alright and another thing with this
covered 19 we want to save as many
Filipinos as we can that's why we do
have products online when you go to the
website of FWD we do have this what be
called product nut conduce meaning that
candice is something like me renewable
every year you know so me so we can just
simply buy it and we're going to tell
you that later because you're gonna ask
the products later right so these are
the things these are the things that we
are doing to mitigate the risk meaning
that we still continue to serve and
protect Filipinos at this point in time
Wow say that really resonates with me
especially coming from the tech industry
this services right now is very hard to
do services right but you do have to do
it face to face hospitality industry has
been hit so badly that tourism industry
restaurants closing down so there's a
lot of businesses affected by this
pandemic and it's just at this time we
have always been a tech industry
advocating to product ice your service
they always product ice your service but
and then after with your product eyes
your service you have to digitize your
product so it with with what FWB has
been doing no insurance it's very
service oriented
however it'd be you profit you
productize that service by having you
know online platforms and having your
own app and things like that
which is also very really but in this
day of age so that really resonates with
me in terms of how FWD is really popping
up with the times and and and that's
that's why so for our customers I mean
for our audience out there it's also
maybe because I'm also a FWD client and
that's just resonates with me so so now
let's talk about why FWD so because
there's a lot of insurance companies out
there so I'm just playing the devil's
advocate I'm already your client right
so for those out there who are not we're
thinking as you know I already have a
life insurance prior to purchasing FWD
but then you know what they really saw
was the service or stop there I just
know paying monthly for for what my
premium was but not really understanding
where it's gonna come from it's just
like ok it's just an investment and
they'd I know my family would get
something it's just like that but I
really saw know that differentiator of
them would be from my previous you know
provider which is still know as you have
mentioned as well you did it Batman
then cut them off just you it's an
addition to what they currently have so
yeah I give you the floor so why FWD for
our audience out there ok Oh Jay in fact
before that was also my question in my
mind
why should I join FWD because aniseh
speaking FWD is my fave
life insurance company and I've made
already some you know cake comparison
and you know and I made the right
possession of joining F EE D F so I'm so
proud I take pride and pleasure and in
fact it is a blessing for me that I join
FWD why because F EE D for me is
actually relevant to these times and for
the incoming for the coming years right
now what makes me at sure what attracted
me to F EE D is the system you know even
after the we fw b as Trini is a member I
just want to give you as the we who is
after we do K can I just give you so
that the audience will know who is FWD
FWD so a lot of people would mistake it
as an abbreviation it's not an
abbreviation it is just like a branding
no so FWD us is not an abbreviation it
stands for fresh and innovative approach
to insurance it is a member of the
Pacific century group based in Hong Kong
we're in fact the owner of this is the
younger son of the richest man in Hong
Kong so Lika shake so the owner was
Richard Lee and the Pacific century
group the partner of Pacific century
group is Swiss Ray who is this one of
the largest insurers in the world and in
terms of F the wedi assets group assets
because we are present in an Asian
countries like its base in Hong Kong
Macau Singapore of Japan Indonesia
Indonesia Vietnam and we do have silent
and recently of course Philippines and
recently last year is West Malaysia and
soon to open East Asia I know China so
that's it now the teutuls fwe group
group assessed it was is about 30
billion US dollars we are such a very
big company and various financial stable
and in the Philippines
it came to the Philippines in 2014 in
September of 2014 it was not
WD that actually you know not select in
covered at hey I would like to expand my
business than the Philippines no it's
not like that
is insurance it's the flippin government
that invited FWD to come to expand their
business in the Philippines so with that
in 2014 I'm so proud that FWD is
considered their fastest-growing life
insurance company in the Philippines why
FWD is the fastest growing life
insurance company in the Philippines
it's five times faster than the than
overall industry growth in terms of new
business in 2018 right we're at number
eight out of 30 companies in terms of
new business and it's only four four
four years of operations 15 16 17 18
all right and not only that not only
that we are the highest capitalized
speed update up we have the biggest
capitalization of having 2.3 billion
cases
so among the 30 life insurance companies
in the Philippines so we are the highest
in capital peda
okay so that makes FWD that is a
testament a living testament that FWD is
very committed to stay the Philippines
and serve the Filipino people and we are
here to stay because we are because
capital paid up is what you call
considered as a legal reserve fund that
in case all the clients the same time we
do have the money that is ready to be
given to the beneficiary so that's how
important capital paid up as well all
right so now let's let's go into the
meat of your products and services that
that you offer I think my question would
be when is the the best time to get an
insurance when you started working
when you start to have a family well
what's what's your advice for for those
maybe in their 20s or looking into know
they're thinking probably no that's
that's for a married guy to do that
because you have to secure your family's
future or even if you're starting out
the family if you want to get your own
house first
or what's what's it what's the best time
to to get an insurance when you become
an adult all right
Oh Jay basically there is basically when
you talk about when you when are you
wish should be ready when she you should
be ready to buy life insurance I would
say that now it should that may be now
it must be yesterday meaning in fact the
most employers law when you are born
even 15 days old you can start already
buying a life insurance when you're when
you're 50 because we accept 15 days old
now when you talk about life insurance
it is across ages all ages why because
each life has an economic value so that
moment that you live there must be a
life insurance actually however I would
say that in terms of income capacity
for the young people yes doesn't the
moment that they earn income the moment
that they start earning income they
should buy life insurance all right
why because why because in life
insurance you put 10 imagine if you're
single
the moment you buy and the earn you have
to put to set aside a certain amount of
your money because it has been studied
that you know when you talk about life
insurance it's not just simply
protecting your incompetence also
growing your money at the same time
right and it is going to give you a
buffer at the same time meaning that in
case of emergencies crisis you will have
the money because you know the the
mindset of it
they just simply live my life insurance
if there's an excess you know if you
have extra funds well in fact it's not
because to you talk about the very basic
essence of achieving financial
independence the very basic formula is
actually like this income minus savings
is equal to expense
you should set aside even 10 to 20
percent of your income so that by that
time there will be crisis like
unforeseen risk like this for example
coffee it's also and for seniors if
people don't bother to save money they
will be ending up you know like hand to
mouth existence now they will release
suffer you know and then here is that
when you're going to build a family of
course everybody's going to you know to
build a family that's the time you
because in every stage and life dress
also what you call up what you call a
certain need so for example if you're
getting married of course you start
building or your family that's where you
can see people that there is really a
need to buy a life insurance why because
it's not about you anymore when you
build a family it's not about you
anymore it's about the people you love
because less insurance I would say that
it is about the people you love and you
who who are living because when you die
of course your the people you love must
continue living right so the best time I
would say old Jay is
in fact yesterday so it should have been
it could have been so those people are
watching right now who don't have life
insurance of course it is a must now
that they should have one why because
knowing that life is a risk
the only way for you to get protected is
through life insurance is when they when
they live in the u.s. it's very normal
for them like we would ask you know oh
now what's your insurance it's not if
you have insured so what is your
insurances so so when I was in the US
they were asking what is your insurance
that's not the question is if you have
insurance here the Philippines do you
have insurance or not because they I was
living they expect that you would that
you have already an insurance policy
right so but here in our country is it
possible for minimum wage earners to
afford life insurance that's the case
because if we're going to to have
economic comparison the both countries
definitely there's a big disparity
between the two so would you even
recommend minimum wage earners to no get
a portion of how little they earning and
invest in life insurance
so is that even possible is there a
product is affordable for them to do so
yeah actually Oh Gino I would say that F
EE D is actually catering to all classes
in the society now for example for the
daily H were for the daily wage earners
we do have this product that is actually
that can be bought online this time
alright so in fact we do have a product
that is one two thousand a year so we do
have this product that it's only seven
pesos they can already be protected
yes it can be protected already a for
example we do but this is online product
but this is really what you call
renewable meaning every year you're
gonna buy this product in order so we
don't have this variance there are
different variances meaning if you want
to be covered only when we do have this
product that can cover you with
critically from critical illnesses and I
think that's 100,000 or 200,000 and the
client is just going to pay less than
2,000 a year so that's not bad and then
we have the group life insurance that
having the cost of death yeah yeah yeah
whatever is whatever the cost of death
we cover you and we do have there's also
PI up with a hospitalization so we do
have this products that are catered to
the lowest class of the society like
having seven pesos per day we can we can
cater to that now we can also cater even
of course know from the lowest up to
also do the high net worth clients we
can offer it to them now I would like to
give you our products so the products
that I told you that the online products
that we have that they don't need to use
then just simply go to our website we
just give you the the agents code
because of course the agent should also
are you know because business so we just
simply give you the link link and then
you just simply with a link you're the
client can go can proceed buying already
the insurance in the online by just I
think that's one seventy nine one seven
nine nine only I here can just imagine
that so anybody even help
anybody can just buy this product no
hassle free no need to talk to an an
agent
okay now we do have those products that
second is a we do have this what you
call flagship product oh I'm so proud
that for me this is the best product in
the market in terms of critical illness
we do have this what your product the
set for health the set for health the
one that you bought from me that's the
best product that I would say the best
product why because it covers you off it
covers you with 42 major critical
illnesses up up to three times meaning
three times meaning you can be covered
because the 42 products were actually
grouped into five groups okay so the
five groups so if your if the client is
sick with cancer for example our company
is going to provide also the second
claim of your cancer after five years
that you are cancer-free if your client
is cancer-free for five years after that
if the cancer you know like recurs so
the company will pay you the second time
now it's only for to place your cancer
but what is the cancer because according
diba based on statistics those people
are who are critically ill already are
prone to getting sick all right so what
if the cancer will lead to complications
like med stroke like the terminal
illness meaning terminal illness many
times me for months to live okay you're
still alive but only only given to about
sakai of six months to live so the
company will give the third claim which
is for example you covered with two
million another two million so how much
is that six million already
now what if and you're covered up to age
75 imagine that it's identified but the
moment you get critically ill for the
first time upon first diagnosis the
company will waive your future premiums
that's why I suggest to the young people
to get the 20 years payment why because
it is like you know like betting
your life if you if you get sick after
two years or three years because it's
never a guarantee in life even you're
healthy you seem healthy now but what if
two to three years from now you get
cancer whatever critical illness you
have so now what happens is that it's
going to fully play your plan then the
next time for example you're critically
ill you're terminally ill already then
upon death before reaching it's about a
five the family can get another hundred
percent making it four hundred percent
benefit and not only that in the moment
from the moment that there is what you
call critical a minor critical illness
you get additional a 20% and absolutely
free and what's the good news is that if
you talk about critical illness or
health insurance it's a throwaway plan
right if ever because if ever you don't
get sick and you cannot claim the
whatever you pay is a thrown away or had
thrown away already you cannot get back
what you paid but what good thing about
our product set for health is that you
can get hundred percent of the premiums
paid no questions asked
she's just like it's just like saving in
the band no so you can get back all the
premiums at age 75 if there is no major
critical illness claim another product
is that we do have the set for life the
set for life is a very common vul
valuable unit link meaning is an if
retraction plus investment right so
you're gonna be protected in sun
protection there's a life insurance
component plus the investment it's just
like buying a life insurance plus a
mutual fund so just to make it simpler
no so the rest of the money will be
invested in stocks in stock market or in
bonds no so so that is it so we do have
that if you wanna grow your money this
is the best time to grow the money with
a coffee nineteen actually the pandemic
with a pandemic don't you know that the
market is very low now but
if you are looking at the perspective of
the investor this is the best time to
invest alright because you can why more
units and your money grow because you
can remember the economy crush in the in
the u.s. last time in 2009 2008 Bayer
mm-hmm yeah I did buy the the the stock
might get really further in fact in my
kind is 2.70 piece so the people who
bought one piece of for example 100 one
peso per unit and then the market
dropped it the one peso became 70 cents
so the clients the investors already
lost but it's just a paper loss but look
at three to four years after that those
people were invested at the time made
300% return of their other investment
so that's the essence also so here in
this aspect there's what you call
blessing in disguise
the Koch the pandemic could be a
blessing in disguise also for for the
investors out there so this is the best
time for you to invest alright and the
third one get us a set for life and the
third one is that that I'm going to
promote to the market is that we do have
this product that is what you call set
for two more if you know this our
products are set for tomorrow set for
tomorrow is going is actually a
temporary life insurance
meaning that you pay and then it's about
death but what's good thing what is the
twist of our temporary insurance you
don't need to die in order to get the
benefit you yourself the client insured
owner insured can get the benefit for
example 10 million example I just give
you an example
oh gee no I have this client 50 years
old a businessman you know what the 12.5
mean because our our our numbered
authority we can insure people up to age
50 at 1.5 million without medical so not
12.5 million the client is only paying
11 thousand a year it's just even lower
than the car insurance so people buy in
car insurance right it's part of their
it's really part of their budget every
year I have to buy back my insure car
insurance for insurance but the
forget that they also have to need need
to insure the driver the owner of the
car so we do have this product that if
you want a very cheap product because
our people who are investors they need
to grow okay Stella
I want to grow my money I am a
businessman and making 100 percent a
year so they cannot buy my product the
vul because they know how to invest
their money see in the prospect I'm
gonna sell the protection because I'm
telling the client so hey you know how
to make money I don't know how to make
money like you do but the only thing
that I can do for you to add and what
value I can add to you is I'm gonna
protect the money that you're making
meaning I'm gonna protect you when
everything falls then the life insurance
is going to protect you and preserve
your assets now so that's it so we'd
have this product and you don't need to
die to get this right if you're quick
terminally ill for example 10 million or
12.5 million it will be given to you
while you are still alive and another
thing is that another twist of this
product is that it has 12.5 it's going
to be extended to the spouse if ever the
client died if the couple dies in
accident at the same time within 90 days
whatever is the coverage of the spouse
will be extended Duda to the hood up
their spouse so the husband coverage is
extended to the wife's cover two wipes
life meaning kunuk if you do have 12 and
5 million coverage in the entire your
wife there are a year of spouse dies
with you then 12.5 times 2 this 25
million so that's a lot so that's also
that twice of our product so we do have
these are the products that I would say
that really that is really competitive
in the market that everyone should look
into because as I would say that we have
because our vision is to change the way
people feel about insurance and that's
how we position all our products it's
very very inspiring and how you
communicate that really the passion in
the thing that you do really show
in your presentation so so for our
audience out there we're actually doing
a one-to-one because we're a member of
this organization called B&I wherein you
are required to do a one-to-one with a
fellow member and let's talk about that
right now and then about why we're doing
this we want to know more about each
other's businesses this is what the
organization is all about so I think my
only question for you for for for BNI is
why did you join BNI and and for
business owners out there and
professionals and independent
distributors what how would be a member
of this organization would also help
them out in their businesses
okay basically in every business we need
market we need clients customers and I
don't remain reason why I joined B and I
because I do believe that I can expand
my network right and not only that
because it's such a simply expanding
network because knowing that this is a
referral organization we are expected
that when you meet up you're only
talking about business it's really worth
your time it's one or any half and
actually it was a challenge for me it is
for me and for the first time because
I'm a you know I don't usually wake up
early so because the meeting requires to
be at 7 o'clock right and you need to be
in the middle that's the really the very
that is the challenge of being an BNI
but I would say having been in BNI for
more than two years now I would say that
I made the right decision to be part of
the B and I because you know what along
the way because I like the the
philosophy of givers game I always
believe in that in fact it is also my
personal value that you don't need to
expect meaningly something that you have
to help first before you can be helped
meaning that you have to give it is in
giving that you can receive right so I
always believe that when you give more
you receive more so that's the concept
of BNI that you're going to help each
member grow their business at the same
time and in return you're also growing
your business at the same time but
another thing on also is that it's very
important as it in BNI it's not just
simply making about money but is also
making or building long lasting
relationships we are not just simply an
organization but as a family as well
because we are here to support each
other and care for each other you know
so when I joined be an I definitely
because in my case I was like I was very
new and FWD because I joined FWD in 2018
so basically I did I ran out of market
I would say huh I mean I don't have my
cat any more dental my cat anyway I
don't know where to oh so I need to
expand so I saw the opportunity OB and I
so in the process I was able to know new
people and these new people we
introduced me to their friends you know
told their colleagues so basically it's
multiplying effect there's a multiplying
effect meaning that it is not just
talking about we are 22 members 24
members but with our 24 members you can
just imagine if 24 members are
multiplied times 2 then then times 2 so
X exponential growth so that's I saw in
B and I that's why I drawing and and I
love the I love the camaraderie in our
organization so our organizations be an
eye investment chapter where the second
our chapter that was organized in the in
the region and I'm very happy I would
like to mention my friend mrs. Espinoza
the one the owner of our builders she's
really my good friend and client she is
the one who invited me to be an eye and
I was so grateful I'm so grateful and
forever and grateful to her for
introducing me this very amazing
opportunity to be part of the be and I
okay so I think that's all the time we
have for this episode and do you have
any last words or advice to the business
in general who's now experiencing the
struggles amidst this pandemic
especially those young people who are
just trying out who who do their
businesses and then BOOM here's this
pandemic well what would you advise them
know basically with the pandemic right
now we always have to look at the
positive side of it you know you have to
focus on your goals and your dreams you
focus
what you can control rather than
focusing on the things that you cannot
control pandemic is beyond our control
but if you allow this fear to overcome
you and the anxiety to overcome you
you will lose so this time make it as
something look at always the positive
side that that our silver lining in the
silver lining there is what you call I
always remember that this will not last
long this is just a temporary this is
temporary so this will pass so hang on
and focus and focus on all the things
that you can control and be positive and
and be optimistic that somewhere out
there there's a rainbow because every
after storm
there's a rainbow there's hope that
things will just turn out better after
this after this pandemic so never lose
hope there is always a rainbow at the
end of this after the end of the storm
Thank You Stella Cibola everybody
FWB insurance thank you very much for
raising us with your presence and very
candidly presenting to us your business
and and of course your your life
experiences as well so me Stella thank
you very much for for being in the show
thank you thank you Oh J for the support
unity I love it
see you soon I see you see the next week
okay thank you next week and I'm og
Lopez with business one two one's saying
that that big dream would have not been
put inside of you if you don't have the
capacity to achieve
[Music]